Guide to the Natural History Society records, 1876-1994.
Natural History Society records, 1876-1994.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Natural History Society records, 1876-1994.
37-6-584
Natural History Society (Cornell University)
1.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, minutebooks, papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minute books (1876-1898), ledger, containing the Society's constitution with amendments, and a membership list which gives some information about some of the individual members; correspondence, publicity, accounts, photographs, and other manuscripts.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Natural History Society is also called the Jordani Club, in honor of David Starr Jordan, a former Cornell biologist.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minute books (1876-1898), ledger, containing the Society's constitution with amendments, and a membership list which gives some information about some of the individual members; correspondence, publicity, accounts, photographs, and other manuscripts.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Jordani.; Natural history--Societies, etc.; Minutes.; Constitutions.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Natural History Society Secretary's Record Book, 1876-1892 (Box 1)
- Natural History Society Secretary's Record Book, 1893-1898 (Box 1)
- Natural History Society Constitution and Membership Book, 1869-1896 (Box 1)
- Historian's Book, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Historian's Book, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Historian's Book, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Historian's Book, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Historian's Book, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Historian's Book, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Sample copies of letters; copy of letter by A. H. Wright, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Membership Lists, 1949-1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Book plates, photos, postcards, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Exhibit Publicity (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Event Flyers, 1960s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Event Flyers, 1960s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Event Flyers, 1960s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Event Flyers (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Event Flyers (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Event Flyers (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Constitution and Stationery (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Jordani Newsletter/Journal, 1967-1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- David Starr Jordan - biographical material (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Burt Green Wilder - biographical material (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Louis Agassiz - biographical material (Box 2, Folder 23)
- History of Jordani (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Screen Tours, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Photographs, 1949-1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Field Trips, 1941-1968 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Correspondence and Memos, 1955-1994 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Group Photographs, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1968-1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Membership Lists, 1954-1961 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Correspondence - transfer of Jordani collection to Zoology Library, 1955 and 1959 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Howard Evans publications - "Anatomical History at Cornell" and "Early Cornell Naturalists - Anatomists", 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- David Starr Jordan Prize, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Natural History Society Correspondence and Papers, 1879-1897 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Natural History Society Expenses/Receipts, 1879-1895 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- "Studies in History No. 19: Pre-Cornell and Early Cornell V: Natural History Society of Cornell University 1869-1899" by Albert Hazen Wright; annotated, signed by the author (Box 2)
- "Studies in History No. 28: Pre-Cornell and Early Cornell: David Starr Jordan '72 and Some Cornell College Mates" by Albert Hazen Wright; annotated (Box 2)
- "Studies in History No. 32: Pre-Cornell and Early Cornell XV: The Biological Society of Cornell University (1901-1912)" by Albert Hazen Wright (Box 2)
- Jordani Public Lectures and Programs presented by Members book, 1956-1965 (Box 2)